Lowell Thomas Papers: Objects
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 6. World War I/Travelogues, 1914 - 1918; 6; Boxes: 1713 - 1721
  - World War I flannel-lined leather aviator’s helmet. Laces up the back, adjustable straps with buckles at the chin. Built-in ear flaps accommodate radio headset, and side snaps hold goggles in place. Goggles are hinged for a custom fit, 1914 -1918 (Folder 1, Box 1713)
  - World War I Pickelhaube, standard issue World War I German infantry black spiked helmet. Features fluted spike, cruciform spike base, squared visor rim, brass chin scales and red cockade around chinstrap fitting, 1914 -1918 (Folder 1, Box 1714)
  - World War I Italian “Adrian” M1916 helmet in grey-green painted metal. Helmet made in two pieces: the helmet shell and crest. Liner is Italian made leather with cloth head band in grey-green wool, 1914 -1918 (Folder 1, Box 1715)
  - Ceremonial knife/dagger, hand carved wooden handle with decorative white metal discs. U-shaped stitched leather sheath overlaid with traditional metalwork, circa 1918 (Folder 1, Box 1716)
  - Camel saddle of the Tuareg people, featuring tooled leather with brass decorative strips and incised tin detailing. Measuring approximately 31 x 14 x 37 inches, circa 1918 (Folder 1, Box 1717)
  - Turkish flag (white crescent moon and star on a red background). Very worn; frayed on lower left corner and damaged with numerous holes. Still rolled around a broken piece of the flag standard. Measures approximately 21½ x 36½ inches, circa 1914 -1918 (Folder 1, Box 1718)
  - French flag (tri-colored: red, white and blue). Measures approximately 34½ x 51½ inches, circa 1914 -1918 (Folder 2, Box 1718)
  - Plaster relief of T. E. Lawrence. Measures 7 x 11 x 1½ inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1719)
  - Red eye-glass container measuring approximately 4½ x 2 inches. Company logo inside of case reads “Fort and Goodwin Jewelers, 2 North Broad St., Trenton, N.J.”, circa 1917 - 1918 (Folder 1, Box 1720)
  - Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas’s World War I Red Cross uniform pin; showing wear at the center. Measures ¾ x ¾ inches [the pin is inside item 1 (eye-glass container) where it was originally housed], circa 1917 - 1918 (Folder 2, Box 1720)
  - Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas’s World War I metallic eagle Red Cross uniform pin. Measures 2½ x ¾ inches [the pin is inside item 1 (eye-glass container) where it was originally housed]., circa 1917 - 1918 (Folder 3, Box 1720)
  - Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas’s World War I metallic bar Red Cross uniform pin. Measures 1 x ¼ inches metallic bar. [the pin is inside item 1 (eye-glass container) where it was originally housed], circa 1917 - 1918 (Folder 4, Box 1720)
  - Lowell Thomas’s desert robe. Heavy deep brown wool with intricate golden embroidery on square collar. Tie-front with fine gold thread balls, circa 1918 (Folder 1, Box 1721)
- 7. World War II, 1945; 7; Boxes: 1722 - 1723
  - Lowell Thomas’s World War II uniform jacket in army green wool twill from Luxemburg Civilian & Military Tailors, New York. “War Correspondent” patch appears over left pleated pocket with button-flap. Circular patch on shoulder reads, “U.S. War Correspondent”, circa 1945 (Folder 1, Box 1722)
  - Lowell Thomas’s World War II uniform slacks with custom label containing Lowell Thomas’s name, date of manufacture (3/22/45) and order number (#A7742). Taupe wool twill with side pockets and back inset pocket. Labels contain manufacturer’s information: “Luxemburg Civilian & Military Tailors, New York”, 1945 (Folder 2, Box 1722)
  - Lowell Thomas’s World War II uniform hat, made by Luxemburg Civilian & Military Tailors, 485 Madison Ave., NYC. Green woolen cap with leather brim and hat band with golden spread-winged eagle front-center. Gold fabric interior, size 7 3/8 inches. is signed by Lowell Thomas on the interior gold fabric; his name is printed in black ink on the leather sweat band: “L. Thomas, N.B.C., N.Y.”, circa 1945 (Folder 1, Box 1723)
- 8. Miscellany, 8; Boxes: 1724 - 1743
  Series contains minerals and printing plates
  Type
  - Subseries 8.1: Minerals, 8.1; Boxes: 1724 - 1727
    - A mud brick from the wall of an unearthed house at Mohenjo-Daro in the Upper Indus Valley, undated (Folder 1, Box 1724)
    - A piece of York Minster pillar, undated (Folder 2, Box 1724)
    - Rock with tile (four pieces) as well as a piece of detached sandstone off-white in color, undated (Folder 3, Box 1724)
    - Stone from Richmond Castle. Note: “No question as to how acquired, please?”, 1971 September 14 (Folder 4, Box 1724)
    - Quartz, undated (Folder 5, Box 1724)
    - 2 reddish-pink stones, undated (Folder 6, Box 1724)
    - Two pieces of brownish-orange rock. One appears brick-like, undated (Folder 7, Box 1724)
    - Black striped rock, undated (Folder 8, Box 1724)
    - Several fragments of brown sandstone, undated (Folder 9, Box 1724)
    - Brown sandstone from Reunion Hall at Princeton, undated (Folder 1, Box 1725)
    - Black gneiss from the Firestone Library at Princeton, undated (Folder 2, Box 1725)
    - White marble from Whig Hall at Princeton, undated (Folder 3, Box 1725)
    - Broken piece of Greece pottery; reddish brown in color, undated (Folder 4, Box 1725)
    - Broken Buddha, grayish in color, undated (Folder 5, Box 1725)
    - Cylindrical shaped stonework marked with the letter Q, undated (Folder 6, Box 1725)
    - Bone shaped rock, undated (Folder 7, Box 1725)
    - Reddish-orange piece of brick. Accompanying note states: “St Peter’s Tomb F1”, undated (Folder 8, Box 1725)
    - Shiny grayish-white piece of rock, undated (Folder 9, Box 1725)
    - Stone from the Rock of Cashel. Accompanying note states: “This is a remarkable outcrop of limestone rising 200 feet. It was the seat of Munster kings from 370 until 1101 when King Murtagh O’Brien granted the Rock to the Church. St. Patrick visited Cashel in AD 450 and baptized the King Aengus. The buildings on the Rock include a tenth century round tower, Cormac’s Chapel, the Cathedral, the Hall of the Vicars Choral, and Saint Patrick’s Cross, as well as some modern tombs and enclosing walls”, undated (Folder 10, Box 1725)
    - A piece of the London Bridge. Accompanying note states: “This particular piece came from Sir John Rennie’s (1761-1821) famous five-arch bridge over the Thames River. The stone was removed during demolition. Included with this artifact is information outlining the London Bridge’s history”, undated (Folder 1, Box 1726)
    - Quartz, undated (Folder 2, Box 1726)
    - Several pieces of the window cusps of Happisburgh Church, Norfolk, England, undated (Folder 3, Box 1726)
    - A center piece of decorative flooring from Curium, Cyprus, undated (Folder 4, Box 1726)
    - Mosaic from Salamis in Cyprus, undated (Folder 5, Box 1726)
    - Quartz, undated (Folder 6, Box 1726)
    - Brick, undated (Folder 7, Box 1726)
    - Stone, undated (Folder 8, Box 1726)
    - Stone, undated (Folder 9, Box 1726)
    - Stone, undated (Folder 10, Box 1726)
    - Petrified wood, undated (Folder 1, Box 1727)
    - Lapis Lazuli. Accompanying note states it is from the tomb of Baber at Kabul, undated (Folder 2, Box 1727)
    - Fossil, undated (Folder 3, Box 1727)
    - Quartz left over from the construction of the Quaker Hill Country Club’s fire place, undated (Folder 4, Box 1727)
    - Red stone with bits of quartz left over from the construction of the Quaker Hill Country Club’s fireplace, undated (Folder 5, Box 1727)
    - Brownish-red and gray rock left over from the construction of the Quaker Hill Country Club’s fireplace, undated (Folder 6, Box 1727)
    - Small piece of purple fluorite, undated (Folder 7, Box 1727)
    - Gray rock, undated (Folder 8, Box 1727)
    - Four small stones. [items housed in a box labeled Genuine Powders from the Depot Pharmacy, Victor, Colorado], undated (Folder 9, Box 1727)
  - Subseries 8.2: Printing plates, 1933 - 1941; 8.2; Boxes: 1728 - 1730
    Series contains images of softball, travelogues, Tibet, Kabluk of the Eskimo, Lowell Thomas, Jr. Literary Digest, and Miscellany
    Original Order/Alphabetical/Chronological/Subject
    - Subseries 8.2.1: Softball, 1933 - 1941; 8.2.1; Boxes: 1728 - 1730
      - Baseball field lined with people. Measures 3½ x 4½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 1, Box 1728)
      - Man seated on ground, member of the softball team. Measures 3½ x 3½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 2, Box 1728)
      - Man in flannel shirt up at bat. Measures 4¾ x 2 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 3, Box 1728)
      - Man catching the ball while another slides into base. Measures 3½ x 4½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 4, Box 1728)
      - A man running. Measures 3½ x 4½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 5, Box 1728)
      - A profile of a member of the softball team. The cap is in a backwards position. Measures 4½ x 3¼ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 6, Box 1728)
      - Lowell Thomas and President Franklin Delano Roosevelt. Measures 3½ x 4½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 7, Box 1728)
      - A sign states “Softball…So What?” Measures 1½ x 8 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 8, Box 1728)
      - Three men. Measures 7½ x 9 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 9, Box 1728)
      - Ballplayer with his hat sideways. Measures 12 x 9 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 10, Box 1728)
      - A group of boys. Measures 12 x 9 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 11, Box 1728)
      - Three children at a table in a library. Measures 12 x 9 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 12, Box 1728)
      - Boys lying down in the sand. Measures 12 x 9 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 13, Box 1728)
      - Boys lying down in the sand. Measures 12 x 9 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 14, Box 1728)
      - Anna May Wong playing softball. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, 1937 August 16 (Folder 1, Box 1729)
      - Anna May Wong talking to a man. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, 1937 August 16 (Folder 2, Box 1729)
      - Anna May Wong shaking hands with a man [Lowell Thomas?]. Measures 4¾ x 3½ inches, 1937 August 16 (Folder 3, Box 1729)
      - A man adjusting his suspenders. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 4, Box 1729)
      - A man catching a ball. Measures 5½ x 4-5 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 5, Box 1729)
      - Three men riding on burros. Measures 3¼ x 4¾ inches, 1937 (Folder 6, Box 1729)
      - Profile of a man wearing a cap. Measures 4¾ x 3½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 7, Box 1729)
      - Men on baseball field. Measures 4¾ x 3½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 8, Box 1729)
      - A man in uniform standing next to woman with members of the softball team behind them. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 9, Box 1729)
      - A man with back turned speaking with a woman. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 10, Box 1729)
      - A man holding a bat. Measures 4 x 2/ ½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 11, Box 1729)
      - Three men. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 12, Box 1729)
      - A man receiving a hotdog at the softball barbeque. Measures 3½ x 4 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 13, Box 1729)
      - Two men lying on the ground. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 14, Box 1729)
      - Three men and a small girl. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 15, Box 1729)
      - A softball team. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 16, Box 1729)
      - Four men seated. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 17, Box 1729)
      - A softball team. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 18, Box 1729)
      - Two men talking. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 19, Box 1729)
      - Maine Lumberjacks musical troupe next to an automobile. Measures 3½ x 4½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 20, Box 1729)
      - People on a lunch line at a softball barbeque. Measures 5 x 3¼ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 21, Box 1729)
      - Several seated men with one holding a radio. Measures 3½ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 22, Box 1729)
      - A man dressed in a costume with a dollar symbol wearing a star hat. He also appears to be holding a wand. Measures 4½ x 3½ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 23, Box 1729)
      - A three-quarter profile of a man. Measures 3¾ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 24, Box 1729)
      - A large crowd of people. Measures 5¾ x 9 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 25, Box 1729)
      - Heywood Broun swinging the bat with the catcher behind him. Measures 7½ x 9 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 1, Box 1730)
      - A man up at bat [Heywood Broun?]. A woman is standing next to him. Measures 3¾ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 2, Box 1730)
      - Lowell Thomas dressed as a cowboy as part of his Nine Old Men softball team. Robert Ripley is beside Thomas. Measures 5¼ x 7¼ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 3, Box 1730)
      - Softball team; Lowell Thomas is sitting on the ground. Measures 2¾ x 4¼ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 4, Box 1730)
      - Babe Ruth swinging a bat. Wooden block measures 5½ x 5 inches [circular plate], circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 5, Box 1730)
      - Woman in catcher’s pose. Measures 4¼ x 2¼ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 6, Box 1730)
      - Woman swinging a bat. Measures 5 x 2¼ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 7, Box 1730)
      - Man with a mustache swinging a bat. There is a small crowd behind him. Measures 3¾ x 5 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 8, Box 1730)
      - Two men talking. On the far end is a man with a cap and shirt with the number 20 on it as well as a man in a sports coat and tie. Measures 3¼ x 4¼ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 9, Box 1730)
      - A man up at bat. Measures 4½ x 2 inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 10, Box 1730)
      - Three men ridding burros. Measures 3¾ x 4¾ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 11, Box 1730)
      - Eleanor Roosevelt with Westbrook Pegler. Measures 9½ x 7½ inches, 1933 (Folder 12, Box 1730)
      - Robert L. Johnson correspondence. Measures 7½ x 5¼ inches, circa 1933 - 1941 (Folder 13, Box 1730)
    - Subseries 8.2.2: Travelogues, 1919 - 1923; 8.2.2; Box: 1731
      - General Allenby and his wife. Measures 3¾ by 4½ inches, circa 1919 (Folder 1, Box 1731)
      - Man on a camel next to a palm tree. Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 10 x 2¼ inches, circa 1919 (Folder 2, Box 1731)
      - “Come to the Land of Enchantment.” Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 3½ by 4½ inches, circa 1919 (Folder 3, Box 1731)
      - “Come to the Land of Enchantment,” Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 3 x 4½ inches, circa 1919 (Folder 4, Box 1731)
      - “Come to the Land of Enchantment in the Carnagey-Timothy Tours of the World.” Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 1½ x 4 inches, circa 1919 (Folder 5, Box 1731)
      - “With Allenby in Palestine - On no stage of whatever kind had been presented anything more impressive and fascinating. The Morning Post London.” Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 6½ x 4½ inches, circa 1919 (Folder 6, Box 1731)
      - Soldier and woman dressed in Arab garments, camel in background Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 2¼ x 3½ inches, circa 1919 (Folder 7, Box 1731)
      - Lowell Thomas and T. E. Lawrence in Arab robes. Measures 5 x 4 inches, circa 1919 (Folder 8, Box 1731)
      - An individual being fanned by another, incense burning on right. Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 1 x 4 inches, circa 1919 (Folder 9, Box 1731)
      - “Come to the land of enchantment.” Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 2 x 4½ inches, circa 1919 (Folder 10, Box 1731)
      - Lowell Thomas on horseback. Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 4 x 4¼ inches, circa 1919 (Folder 11, Box 1731)
      - Several camels in a row. Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 1¼ x 4 inches, circa 1919 (Folder 12, Box 1731)
      - Lowell Thomas on camelback. Used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 3¼ x 3¾ inches, circa 1919 (Folder 13, Box 1731)
      - “Lowell Jackson Thomas Greatest Alaskan Travelogue.” The print contains snow covered mountain tops with a body of water and Lowell Thomas dressed in a bear suit standing next to a dog. Measures 7¾ x 5 and 2¼ inches, circa 1915 - 1916 (Folder 14, Box 1731)
      - Three plates of Lowell Thomas probably from the early days of the travelogues. Measures 9¼ x 3¾ inches, circa 1919 - 1923 (Folder 15, Box 1731)
      - Portrait of Lowell Thomas used for his travelogues. Measures 4½ x 3 inches, circa 1919 - 1923 (Folder 16, Box 1731)
      - Print of a man in a suit wearing a hat. Used for Hindustan or Through Romantic India travelogue. Measures 3½ by 2 inches, circa 1923 (Folder 17, Box 1731)
      - A person wearing beads, holding a stick with a tea kettle on it. Possibly used for the Romantic India travelogue. Measures 3½ x 4½ inches, circa 1923 (Folder 18, Box 1731)
      - Man in Arab[?] garments tugging at a stubborn animal. Possibly used for With Allenby in Palestine and with Lawrence in Arabia travelogue posters, advertisements and promotional brochures. Measures 3½ x 1½ inches, circa 1920s (Folder 19, Box 1731)
    - Subseries 8.2.3: Tibet, 1949; 8.2.3; Boxes: 1732 - 1738
      - Lhasa street scene. [4 copies] Measures 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1732)
      - Corresponding caption plate for item 3 below. Measures 1¼ x 1¼ inches, 1949 (Folder 2, Box 1732)
      - Lowell Thomas standing next to unidentified man; caption: “There were many fascinating sights to be seen on the rocky road to Lhasa. So many, in fact, that the travelers don’t seem to have shaved every morning.” [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 3, Box 1732)
      - Caption: “Paying with Tibetan copper coins the coolies who helped us on one day’s journey. Their daily wage, less than fifty cents, is a good sum in the Orient.” [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 4, Box 1732)
      - Chief abbot, the Jokang in the distance. Caption: “The chief abbot of the Jokang poses against the background of its golden roof. In Lhasa the cathedral, politically important, stands beside the Foreign Office.” [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 5, Box 1732)
      - Split plate - one of the “Rice Heap” and the other of “Jewel Park.” The “Rice Heap” is the Drepung monastery. “The Jewel Park” was photographed with five high lamas who served as advisers to the Dalai Lama. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 5 inches, 1949 (Folder 6, Box 1732)
      - Split plate - one of a Tibetan abbey and the other of Lowell Thomas and Dorje Changwaba. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 5 inches, 1949 (Folder 7, Box 1732)
      - Interior of a Sera Temple. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 8, Box 1732)
      - The home of Tsarong Shape. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½inches, 1949 (Folder 9, Box 1732)
      - Split plate - one of a Tibetan woman wearing a silk dress and hat and the other of a person painting a Buddha. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 5 inches, 1949 (Folder 10, Box 1732)
      - Lowell Thomas and the rescue team. Front row: Major A.K. Bose, nurse Emily Bateman, Roy Bisbee and Dr. Pal. [4 copies] Measures approximately 2 x 3 inches, 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1733)
      - Corresponding caption plate for item 1 above. Measures ¾ x 2 inches, 1949 (Folder 2, Box 1733)
      - A plate containing three images: One image is of shaggy, buffalo-like yaks on the plain of Phari; another is of Lowell Thomas in an improvised sedan with Dr. Pal on the left and Captain Patil at right; the third is of common folks at Lhasa. [4 copies] Measures approximately 5½ x 5 inches, 1949 (Folder 3, Box 1733)
      - A bazaar at Lhasa. [4 copies] Measures approximately are 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 4, Box 1733)
      - Lhasa monastery with a monk spinning a prayer wheel. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 5, Box 1733)
      - Lowell Thomas on the outskirts of Lhasa. In the distance is the Potala Palace. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 6, Box 1733)
      - The Dalai Lama’s family. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 7, Box 1733)
      - Monks serving as the Dalai Lama’s personal bodyguard. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 8, Box 1733)
      - The aged abbots of Drepung Gompa. [4 copies] Measures approximately 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 9, Box 1733)
      - A Tibetan army general. [4 copies] Measures approximately 2 x 3 inches, 1949 (Folder 10, Box 1733)
      - Corresponding caption plate for item 10 above. Measures 1 x 1¼ inches, 1949 (Folder 11, Box 1733)
      - Woman and her daughter overlooking the Holy City. [4 copies] Measures approximately 2 x 3 inches, 1949 (Folder 12, Box 1733)
      - Corresponding caption plate for item 12 above. Measures 1¼ x 1¼ inches, 1949 (Folder 13, Box 1733)
      - Yak-buttered tea in a porcelain cup. [4 copies] Measures approximately 2 x 3 inches, 1949 (Folder 14, Box 1733)
      - Corresponding caption plate for item 14 above. Measures 1½ x 1½ inches, 1949 (Folder 15, Box 1733)
      - The Dalai Lama flanked by chrysanthemums. On the right is the regent Tokra. [4 copies] Measures approximately 4½ x 7½ inches, 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1734)
      - Panchen Lama. [43 copies] Measures approximately 4½ x 7½ inches, 1949 (Folder 2, Box 1734)
      - Three men who are members of the Kashag. [4 copies] Measures approximately 4½ x 7½ inches, 1949 (Folder 3, Box 1734)
      - Corresponding caption plate for item 3 above. Measures ½ x 7½ inches, 1949 (Folder 4, Box 1734)
      - Monk who acts as proctor at the Sera monastery in Lhasa. [4 copies] Measures 2 x 3 inches, 1949 (Folder 5, Box 1734)
      - Lowell Thomas stopping a noble on horseback. [3 copies] Measures 3 x 4½ inches, 1949 (Folder 6, Box 1734)
      - An actor playing a demon attacking a high ranking lama during the summer festival. [4 copies] Measures 2 x 3 inches, 1949 (Folder 7, Box 1734)
      - The stone staircase leading into the main temple of Potala. [4 copies] Measures 4½ x 3 inches, 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1735)
      - Corresponding caption plate for item 1 above. Measures 1 x 1¼ inches, 1949 (Folder 2, Box 1735)
      - Across the valley from the Potala. [8 copies] Two measure approximately 3½ x 7½ inches; two measure approximately 4½ x 7½ inches; four larger ones measure 10½ x 11 inches, 1949 (Folder 3, Box 1735)
      - Handmade wooden crate that originally housed Tibet printing plates. Measures approximately 10½ x 8½ x 7½ inches, 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1736)
      - Handmade wooden crate that originally housed Tibet printing plates. Measures approximately 10½ x 8½ x 7½ inches, 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1737)
      - Handmade wooden crate that originally housed Tibet printing plates. Measures approximately 10½ x 8½ x 7½ inches, 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1738)
    - Subseries 8.2.4: Kabluk of the Eskimo, 1932; 8.2.4; Boxes: 1739